Ahmad M.N. Zaza

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Doha, DA

Phone

+974 33297349

E-mail

me@ahmadmnzaza.com

www

ahmadmnzaza.com

Skills

Skilled in Programming Languages (Python, Java, C, C++, C#)

Database Management (SQL and NoSQL)

API design knowledge (REST)

Web Application Frameworks (VueJS, React, Angular, and ASP.NET)

Mobile Development (Kotlin and Swift)

Search Engines (ElasticSearch)

Application Server (Tomcat, JBoss, WildFly)

Version Control (SVN and Git)

Blockchain (Bitcoin, Ethereum, Monero)

Machine Learning (TensorFlow, SciKit)

Lightweight Servers (SpringBoot, NodeJS/NPM)

Network Configuration (Cisco and Huawei Certified)

MVC Architecture

Cloud Computing (AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud)

Languages

Arabic (Mother Tongue)

English (Advanced)

Chinese (Beginner)

Spanish (Elementary)

Versatile Software Developer and Team Manager, currently pursuing a Master's degree in Networking and security, with over 3 years of experience in Fullstack Programming (Web apps or Mobile apps) and Software Engineering. Self-directed leader with expertise in Backend Development and Project Management. Talented at cultivating collaborative and supportive team environment.

Work History

2020-04 -Current

Software Developer

QMIC

- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality and function prior to release.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Developed and maintained 3 Fullstack web applications to be used in house and for outside customers.

2019-06 -2020-05

Software Developer

Ogoul Technology

- Designed new product elements such as image recognition, hand-writing recognition, audio, video and device-to-device communication.
- Trained and managed team of 7 of developers and discussed issues in order to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Administered, supported and monitored databases by proactively resolving database issues and maintaining servers.

2018-10 -2020-08

Research Assistant

Qatar University

- Worked two separate NPRP projects. Worked mainly with Blockchain and Machine Learning technologies while producing 2 publications (In progress of submission).
- Validated incoming data to check information accuracy and integrity while independently locating and correcting concerns.
- Produced 2 working prototypes for different protocols developed during research.

Education

2019-01 -

Master of Science: Computing

Current

Qatar University

- Continuing education in Networking and Security.
- Currently have 3 publications (1st Author).
- Expected graduation: April 2021.

2015-01 -2018-11

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Qatar University

- Started Spring 2015.
- Graduated with 3.57 GPA with Honors.
- Dean's List From 2015 Spring to 2018 Fall.

Accomplishments

- Won "Best Student Project" for multiple course work from 2015 to 2018.
- Participated in GCC Robotics Competition in 2016 (Placed 2nd).
- Interned at **Huawei Headquarters** for a month (December 2018, Shenzhen, China).
- Was part of Marketing and Management team in Graduate Studies
 Office in Qatar University.